Tufts Daily UP029
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Tufts Daily, 1997; UP029.018; 3.6 Linear Feet; 119 Digital Object(s)
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 April 22; UP029.018.029.00015 (Volume 29)
    Fired up over butterflies. Tonight is Hotung:Brenner vs. Matoxx. President hopes to improve image of Tufts Republicans. Jumbos bats' come alive(Baseball).
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 April 23; UP029.018.029.00016 (Volume 29)
    Mattox and Brenner compete in debate for TCU [Tufts Community Union] presidency. social policy at Tufts to be studied this summer. Fellowships awarded to five history professors.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 April 24; UP029.018.029.00017 (Volume 29)
    Mattox wins TCU [Tufts Community Union] presidential election. New center will be focused on family and media environment. No Morrill? No problem! (women's lacrosse). Games important for morale (men's lacrosse).
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 April 25; UP029.018.029.00018 (Volume 29)
    No admission fee can be levied at Goddard. Senior garners first prize in engineering contest. Surf's up at Holy Cross track(Women's track). MIT Baffles Jumbos(men's track). Leonard carmichael Society:Connections.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 April 28; UP029.018.029.00019 (Volume 29)
    Astronaut Hauck receives Light on the Hill tomorrow. Debauchery on the Lawn. Maya Angelou speaks tonight. Mattox outlines initial goals. Sunday afternoon blaze. Womens lacrosse keeps NCAA [National Collegiate Athletic Association] hopes alive. Losing streak at 11(men's lacrosse). A pair of sweet victories for the highly ranked Jumbos (Softball). Spring Fling. Semester in review-Spring 1997.
  - Tufts Daily, Commencement, 1997; UP029.018.029.00020 (Volume 29)
    Tufts to confer almost 2000 degrees today. Astronaut Rick Hauck honored with third Light on Hill award. Faculty reject change in freshman writing requirement. Senate elects executive board during final meeting of the year. Carmichael scheduled for summer repairs. Senate gavel passes to Mattox. University updates its web page. [Marilyn] Glater steps down as dean. DiBiaggio discusses audit, alumni relations. Task force on rae prepares recommendations. [Rev. Michael] Hunt's departure is a loss to many friends and students. Grads bid farewell to Tufts. Seniors' long and winding road. [Tufts baseball team:] winners and still champions. [Softball] Sluggers earn first ever NCAA [National Collegiate Athletic Association] berth, bow out early. Bouced out of [men's tennis] regionals. Jumbos tumble in [women's lacrosse] ECAC [Eastern College Athletic Conference] heartbreaker. [men's lacrosse] looking towards the future. Rowers send three to Georgia. [Mens] Tracksters: A Force to be reckoned with. Surprising spring success [for women's track.] Four years of hard work pays dividends for [Rosalie] Ferrara. Seven Garner recognition at Captains' Luncheon. Next stop: [Sailing] Nationals.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 August 27; UP029.018.029.00021 (Volume 29)
    Class of 2001 matriculates today. UNICCO [University Cleaning Company] protests contract decision. Triples await new class. Tufts fall one spot in ranking of best Universities. Now on map, Jumbos look to continue growth.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 September 02; UP029.018.029.00022 (Volume 29)
    Workers protest hiring of new cleaning service. Students angry over changes in Tufts connection billing plan. Tufts professor receives grant.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 September 04; UP029.018.029.00023 (Volume 29)
    Email passwords stolen. Former UNICCO [University Cleaning Company] workers hold rally by powderhouse. Library article from home. Many students avoid shipping belongings by UPS. Father Hunt feeling better. Gun sounds early for Jumbo [women's cross country] runners. Key [football] players return this fall.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 September 08; UP029.018.029.00024 (Volume 29)
    New choices foster a successful orientation. Students and TUPD differ in accounts of early morning fight. Students learn the art of meditation. With proven veteran players gone, field hockey looks to build future.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 September 10; UP029.018.029.00025 (Volume 29)
    Men's rugby suspended for the fall 1997 season. Junior may press charges. Despite three resignations, Senate off to strong start. Students upset over billing. Password lessons learned. Volleyball wants to be a smash. Cross Country desires a repeat invitation to National spotlight.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 September 12; UP029.018.029.00026 (Volume 29)
    Date set for Thatcher address. De La Soul set to rock campus. Students get copies of 'Times'. Mountain Club may receive additional funding. Groceries for those on the go. Soccer team is confident, ready for a strong season. Searching for Tiger Woods [Golf].
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 September 15; UP029.018.029.00027 (Volume 29)
    Agent describes encounter with Nazis. Neo-Nazi infiltrator set to address campus. Future not looking bright for halogen lamps. Freshmen meet before school. Shir Appeal: singing their way accross campus. Young Jumbos pick up [women's soccer] where they left off. Freshmen swing into early role for lady Jumbos [tennis].
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 September 16; UP029.018.029.00028 (Volume 29)
    Mountain club signs over weekends for next 100 years. Return date uncertain for paralyzed proffessor. Artificial nose being created to sniff out landmines. [Men's] soccer starts off on the right foot. Runners prove to be untouchable in season debut.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 September 17; UP029.018.029.00029 (Volume 29)
    Suspect has not been identified from Saturday's Sig Ep [Sigma Phi Epsilon] incident. Power outage leaves students in the dark. Jumbos head to CA looking for first [volleyball] win. [Field Hockey] Jumbos light up camels.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 September 18; UP029.018.029.00030 (Volume 29)
    TUPD [Tufts University Police Department] emphasizes student awareness in wake of assaults. Tufts' Friedman goes national. One man and his mission. [women's cross country] Starting on the right foot.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 September 19; UP029.018.029.00031 (Volume 29)
    TCU [Tufts Community Union] Senate addresses yearly turnover. FOCUS enters orientation scene. [In Women's soccer] Tufts survives scare.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 September 22; UP029.018.029.00032 (Volume 29)
    Newspapers popular at Tufts, according to Princeton Review. TUTV [Tufts University Television] has plans to begin broadcasting this October. Cardinals run wild all over the Jumbos [football]. Talented freshmen help lead [tennis] team to three victories.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 September 23; UP029.018.029.00033 (Volume 29)
    Professor estimates new age of universe: 12 billion years. President offers cautious defense of fund raising. Rusty water affects Carmichael dining. Womens suffer their first [soccer] loss. Jumbos remain undefeated [men's soccer.]
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 September 24; UP029.018.029.00034 (Volume 29)
    Over enrollment causes late deliveries at bookstore. A stunned Van Camp discusses her time at TUfts. Study abroad in Japan to begin. Fairway to Heaven: Jumbos looking good early.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 September 25; UP029.018.029.00035 (Volume 29)
    Britain's Iron Lady extols democratic system. Senate and CSL [Committee on Student Life] candidates address student electorate. Prez meets the press. Fraternity put on hold. Field Hockey drops another tough game. Jumbos look to gain intensity back home. Team effort paces runners accross.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 September 26; UP029.018.029.00036 (Volume 29)
    Bookstore to expand in size. Executive discusses oil industry future. Eaton, Mark Labs get upgraded. Women's soccer team now 4-1. Smooth sailing, six early wins highlight young Jumbo season. Runner sshaping up for season.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 September 29; UP029.018.029.00037 (Volume 29)
    Smith is winner of Leibner Award. Task force on rae plans to publish report this semester. Donation sustain scholarship fund for state's medical schools. First shuttout in two football seasons for Jumbos. The lost art of kickball.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 September 30; UP029.018.029.00038 (Volume 29)
    Faculty support rehiring of displaced UNICCO [University Cleaning Company] workers. Physical education professor drowns. Jumbos get bounced by Bates. Women net fifth consecutive victory of year.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 October 01; UP029.018.029.00039 (Volume 29)
    TCU [Tufts Community Union] Senate no longer in charge of UNICCO [University Cleaning Company] forum. Banner year for research grants. Ernst replaces Glater as dean.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 October 02; UP029.018.029.00040 (Volume 29)
    Long time educator applauded for work. Tufts tomorrow head looks at progress of campaign today. Wellesley loss hurts post-season hopes [women's soccer]. Women's field hockey at .500. Runners up to fifth in the nation. Without top runner, women still step up.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 October 03; UP029.018.029.00041 (Volume 29)
    Thatcher's security detail very thorough. Administrators and students address alcohol on campus. Finance reform faces obstacles. Prof. Hunter retires after 29 years of service to Tufts. Golf team not up to par at NESCAC [New England Schools and Colleges Athletic Conference] championships. Pats looking to get back to Super Bowl once again.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 October 07; UP029.018.029.00042 (Volume 29)
    Crew team discovers dead body in the Charles river. Tufts, nation discuss global warming issues. [women's soccer] Jumbos tie, score respect. Tufts [women's tennis] stumbles against both rivals, Division I foes.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 October 08; UP029.018.029.00043 (Volume 29)
    Psychology proffesor honored with award. New England conservatory professor, viola virtuoso dies Saturday at age 82. Task force to evaluate campusLink. Jumbos [football] hoping to trample Trinity Bantams on Sunday.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 October 09; UP029.018.029.00044 (Volume 29)
    Student spirit is theme of this years festivities. Children are focus of forum on health. UNICCO [University Cleaning Company] discussion in Ex-college hands. It's deja vu all over again as Bowdoin [field hockey] is held scoreless. Rocky Road leads to .500 mark [for volleyball]. For the long run, [men's cross country] team looks sound. [women's cross country team] Looking to recover from loss.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 October 10; UP029.018.029.00045 (Volume 29)
    Boston council meets to discuss alcohol on campus. [Vee] Talmadge speaks to actors. Public safety department honored with award. Slump sends [men's] soccer skidding. Sailing holding its own.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 October 14; UP029.018.029.00046 (Volume 29)
    Increase in Tuition below national rise. Professors say time travel unlikely. Fletcher graduate speaks on possible NATO enlargement. Jumbos [football] suffer tough loss.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 October 15; UP029.018.029.00047 (Volume 29)
    University to listen to Senate resolutions. Inquiry initiated by cable commission. Students take on the unknown. Grossman introduces Angela Landsbury at the White House. Despite grueling [women's soccer] game, Jumbos emerge victorious on Sunday.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 October 16; UP029.018.029.00048 (Volume 29)
    In wake of state crackdown, liquor stares defend record. Religion department sees faculty enlargement. [Matt] Adler's return ignites [men's] soccer squad, NESCAC [New England Schools and Colleges Athletic Conference]. [Volleyball] finding formula for success and a winning streak.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 October 17; UP029.018.029.00049 (Volume 29)
    1000 fewer parents expected this year. Hospital merger is nearing completion. Faculty, students support ex-UNICCO [University Cleaning Company] workers to teach in. GRE [Grand Requisite Exam] goes high-tech. Manning masters Wellesley [women;s cross counrty] course. A winning weeks for women's tennis team. Heartbreaking loss for Tufts [field hockey]. [men's cross country] Jumbos nipping on the heels of Judges.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 October 20; UP029.018.029.00050 (Volume 29)
    Schools consider SCIRT [Student Coalition for Investor Responsibility at Tufts] resolution. House will vote on student consolodation today. Honors thesis provides alternative to grades. Tufts students take a stand on nuclear abolition. Shock for Jumbos [football defeat].
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 October 21; UP029.018.029.00051 (Volume 29)
    Art History professor [Margaret H. Floyd] dies. President DiBiaggio addresses Senate. Jumbos sail away with two trophies. [Men's] Soccer ties up with Ephmen.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 October 23; UP029.018.029.00052 (Volume 29)
    U.S. diplomat talks on state of Pakistan. Tufts spends thousands on Washington Lobbying firm. TUPD is following leads in aftermath of Sept. 13 assault. Jumbos place above .500 despite defeats [in women's tennis]. Runner sput up stellar times ar the All-New England meet.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 October 24; UP029.018.029.00053 (Volume 29)
    Changes to Homecoming aimed to raise attendance. Committee responds to increase in LD [Learning Disabled] students. Rock and Roll legend Al Kooper leads Blues class. Tufts Alum Eden White to perform this weekend. Jumbos [football] look to dethrone heralded Lord Jeffs. Despite injuries, Altman back. Tennis' terrific two. Gearing up for [field hockey] stretch run. [In soccer,] Men hoping to engineer another victory tomorrow. For Women, [soccer] Amherst is biggest challenge of year. Always in mix, [Evan] Dabby looks to finish career strong. After slide, Jumbo spikers looking to bounce [volleyball] back.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 October 27; UP029.018.029.00054 (Volume 29)
    [Alpha Epsilon Pi] Fraternaties and Sororities receive rating from CFS; No hot showers for Stratton residents over weekend. Homecoming football well attended despite bad weather. Kaplan score centers offer exciting career opportunities. Tufts democrats: more than just campaigning. Records can be decieving: the Jumbos [footbal] have come far. Another frustrating [football] loss.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 October 28; UP029.018.029.00055 (Volume 29)
    State of the Treasury address delivered at senate meeting. [Bud] Collins, [William G.] Grinnell honored by Tufts. Gender may not have swayed Tufts voters. Tufts [women's soccer] dominates, but falls short. Jumbos [men's soccer] triumph.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 October 29; UP029.018.029.00056 (Volume 29)
    ROTC [Reserve Officers' Training Corps] visits Cape for Army training. Hebrew University professor addresses peace in Middle East. DNC [Democratic National Committee] chairman [Steve] Grossman praises grassroots politics. [Danielle] Brennan takes wind out of sails.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 October 30; UP029.018.029.00057 (Volume 29)
    Patriarch brings message of peace to Ellis Oval. Hot water restored in Stratton. Sillers earns NESCAC [New England Schools and Colleges Athletic Conference] honors as Jumbos look for a few [volleyball] wins. On the threshold of NCAA [National Collegiate Athletic Association field hockey] tourney.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 October 31; UP029.018.029.00058 (Volume 29)
    McLennon allows same sex marriages in Goddard. Comments on courses may be on Jumbos Hub. Advisors still in demand for social science majors. Successful Jumbos one kick closer to [women's soccer] playoffs. Strong showing puts [women's] tennis back on map.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 November 03; UP029.018.029.00059 (Volume 29)
    Chinese president lectures at Harvard as part of US tour. High school bands compete on Ellis Oval in rain. More water troubles in Stratton. Jumbos [football] trample White Mules on Saturday.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 November 04; UP029.018.029.00060 (Volume 29)
    Students for labor justice seek TCU [Tufts Community Union] group status. Faculty suggests ways to improve the Tufts Tomorrow Campaign funding. Halogen retro fit kits are available. Defending ECAC [Eastern College Athletic Conference] [field hockey] champs denied NCAA [National Collegiate Athletic Association] invites.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 November 05; UP029.018.029.00061 (Volume 29)
    Co-Authors discuss their book on 'Atomic Bomb Conspiracy'. Tufts students reach out to community. Gloria Feldt speaks on abortion rights. Women: can't ref without 'em. Regular [women's soccer] season ends on down note; team looks to Springfield. St. Mary's Brennan takes the wind out of Tufts sailors.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 November 06; UP029.018.029.00062 (Volume 29)
    With its new look, TUTV [Tufts University Television] hits the air. College Pizza shuts down; competition reacts apathetically. Fifteen students are honored for freshmen year accolades. Jumbos [sailing] snatch bragging rights. Runners hit a valley. Sun shines bright on Tufts [women's soccer]. Jumbos spike their way to big [volleyball] tourney.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 November 07; UP029.018.029.00063 (Volume 29)
    Administration wants to boost commitment to CPC [Career Planning Center]. Mattox plans to propose Junior Trustee program. [Football] Going out with a bang. NCAA [National Collegiate Athletic Association, men's soccer] invitation most likely on the line tomorrow.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 November 10; UP029.018.029.00064 (Volume 29)
    NEMC [New England Medical Center] merger will help fund medical school. Trustees and faculty discuss state of Tufts. UC-Berkley ranks Tufts as 12th most demanding school. Defeat does not detract from successful [women's soccer] season. [Hockey] Teams hopes for NCAAs washed away Saturday. Last-second kick propels Jumbos to [football] victory.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 November 12; UP029.018.029.00065 (Volume 29)
    Actor, social activist [Edward James] Olmos will lecture. Tufts' social policy draws wire of Senate, fraternity members. Honoring America's veterans. [Dr. Terrell] Clark discusses sign language. Austin Pendleton to speak in Balch. [Men's soccer] Downpour by Middlebury. [Men's cross country] Gearing up for upcoming qualifying meet for nationals.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 November 13; UP029.018.029.00066 (Volume 29)
    A fight for the right to party. A quarter-century after Title IX, women's athletics thrive. Serving up more than assignments. Tufts' [Jon] Baker sails to second at nationals. Jumbos set to serve up some trouble at the ECAC [Eastern College Athletic Conference, volleyball] tournament.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 November 14; UP029.018.029.00067 (Volume 29)
    [Austin] Pendleton addresses students in theater. Cousens closed last night following an electrical fire. Study abroad numbers increase. DiBiaggio discusses Berkley rank. Jumbos hand down a harsh [men's] soccer verdict.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 November 17; UP029.018.029.00068 (Volume 29)
    Hip is good, as long as it is not in Harvard square. Brownsfields issue is addressed. Off to the Presses [student publications]. Borghesani prize enhances sense of world commitment. Math Club adds up fun time for all involved.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 November 18; UP029.018.029.00069 (Volume 29)
    Senate discusses social atmosphere on campus. Intruder arrested in South Hall. Program brings minority Ph.d. candidates to speak to students.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 November 19; UP029.018.029.00070 (Volume 29)
    [Edward James] Olmos lectures on diversity. Modern technology is topic of lecture. Field hockey rebounds to end season on good note. Jumbos take two championships (sailing). Like fish in water (water polo).
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 November 20; UP029.018.029.00071 (Volume 29)
    A struggle for preservation. INQUIRY set for April seminar. Oxfam fasts to teach about world hunger. Running 'against the wind' (women's cross country). Jumbos roller-coaster season ends with a defeat in ECACs (volleyball). By slimmest of margins, runners miss Nationals (men's cross country).
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 November 21; UP029.018.029.00072 (Volume 29)
    Foreign policy and refugees discussed. Sign-up begins today for Turkey shuttle. Men's hoops ready to rumble (men's basketball). Jumbos look to improve on last year's 9-13 record (women's basketball).
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 November 24; UP029.018.029.00073 (Volume 29)
    Low pay for faculty, says AAUP data. MOPS hungry for replacement. Harsh end to a strong season (men's soccer).
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 November 25; UP029.018.029.00074 (Volume 29)
    Senate supports NCAA [National Collegiate Athletic Association] post-season play for athletic teams. DiBiaggio reads to promote bookstore. Cultural Solidarity week will promote unity among groups. For starters, Jumbos split (men's basketball). Press and run leads to bid win in opener (women's basketball).
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 November 26; UP029.018.029.00075 (Volume 29)
    Repairs on gym to be completed today. TUPD [Tufts University Police Department] on heightened alert in aftermath of dorm intrusion.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 December 01; UP029.018.029.00076 (Volume 29)
    Making words come alive. Deputy Director of Peace Corps will speak at Tufts. Women diving into season on right note (swimming). Men start off with a huge splash by defeating Clark (swimming).
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 December 02; UP029.018.029.00077 (Volume 29)
    DiBiaggio defends switch of cleaning services to ISS [International Service System.] Trustees' goals for University outlined at faculty meeting. Alpha Phi Delta volunteers in community. Hironaka lights up cats (women's basketball).
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 December 03; UP029.018.029.00078 (Volume 29)
    Groups call new Dewick policy racially motivated. Rugby team is frustrated yet pleased with progress. Turnovers give win to Babson (women's basketball).
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 December 04; UP029.018.029.00079 (Volume 29)
    Former U.S. advisor lectures on roles of science, technology. Strong group plans to jump into ECAC's [Eastern College Athletic Conference] (men's track). Jumbos follow youth into meet (women's basketball). The Greek gazette.
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 October 07; UP029.018.040.00039 (Volume UP029 Shared 2)
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 October 22; UP029.018.058.00059 (Volume UP029 Shared 2)
  - Tufts Daily, 1997 December 05; UP029.018.058.00060 (Volume UP029 Shared 2)
- Tufts Daily, 1989 -- 1998; UP029.019; 3.6 Linear Feet; 93 Digital Object(s)
  - Tufts Daily, 1998 January 14; UP029.019.029.00081 (Volume 29)
    Hundreds of Emerald accounts locked after hackers break in. Food fights prompt end for the annual pancake breakfast. [Sol] Gittleman to undergo hip replacement surgery. Spring 1998: Experimental College Course Offerings.
  - Tufts Daily, 1998 January 16; UP029.019.029.00082 (Volume 29)
    Tufts and UNICCO [University Cleaning Company] hold open dialogue. Santa leaves gift for employees. Brown and Brew celebrates first birthday.
  - Tufts Daily, 1998 January 20; UP029.019.029.00083 (Volume 29)
    Custodial controversy splits administration. Early decision applicants rise. Laundry prices increase. Tufts pledges future of nonviolence on campus. Sickness sweeps ice hockey away (hockey). Mixed bag for road warriors [women's basketball]. Intense training trip leads to solid results (men's swimming). Saints sail away with one (men's basketball).
  - Tufts Daily, 1998 January 22; UP029.019.029.00084 (Volume 29)
    Senate passes change in Campuslink billing plan. Campus groups unite for nonviolence. Madoff honored. 'Cats no match for Tufts (men's basketball). Another road kill served [men's basketball]. Yound swimmers key early success (women's swimming). Bargmann leads way in first two meets for Jumbos (women's track).
  - Tufts Daily, 1998 January 26; UP029.019.029.00085 (Volume 29)
    Research the focus of panel. Roe vs. Wade commemorated at Wednesday's student rally. Fletcher graduate gives advice to students. Tufts drops another sixth straight loss to Vikings (men's basketball). Road-weary Jumbos victorious at home (women's basketball).
  - Tufts Daily, 1998 January 27; UP029.019.029.00086 (Volume 29)